Arnau Saumell

■ +34 682 021 265 | ■ asaumellportillo@gmail.com | 🗥 Homepage | 🛅 arnau-saumell

Personal Profile ____

Undergraduate student of Mathematics and Data Science, at Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC), with academical and professional experience on machine learning, Python development, pure mathematics, statistics and algorithmics. Currently pursuing my Bachelor's Final Thesis at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT).

Education

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

Barcelona, Spain

BS in Mathematics and Data Science

Sept 2018 - Current

- Majoring in both degrees enrolled in an excellence national scholarship program
- · Relevant Courses: Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Image Processing, Probability Theory, Statistics, Differential Equations
- Current Grade: 8.1/10

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

Cambridge, MA, United States

BS Final thesis

Sept 2022 - Current

- Visiting student at MIT for a +6 months stay to develop the final degree thesis.
- Enrolled in the MechE department on a Machine Learning and Robotics related project.
- Working with descriptors for non-rigid/deformable objects, which can give a practical characterization of them and enable their robotic manipulation, from a task-agnostic point of view.

Aula Escola Europea

Barcelona, Spain

National Baccalaureate

September 2016 – June 2018

· Awarded with a full tuition scholarship for academic excellence

Final Grade: 8.2/10

Aula Escola EuropeaBarcelona, Spain

International Baccalaureate (IB)

September 2016 – June 2018

• Awarded with a full tuition scholarship for academic excellence

• Final Grade: 9.0/10

Work Experience ____

Starlab - Neuroscience

Barcelona, Spain

Machine Learning Intern

July 2021 - September 2021 ; January 2022 - March 2022

- Developed the Denoising LSTM Autoencoders for EEG artifact detection and removal project, under the supervision of Dr. Aureli Soria-Frisch.
- Performed signal processing through deep learning for rare events detection and correction.
- · Presented the project in the 2022 INCF Assembly

Informatics and Robotics Institute (IRI)

Barcelona, Spain

Machine Learning Intern

September 2020 – June 2021

- Developed the TASC: Topological Analysis of Simulated Cloth manipulations project, leaded by Dr. Fabio Strazzeri.
- · Performed statistical analysis over a representation of deformable materials based on combinatorial topology
- Implemented Machine Learning approaches in order to achieve a stratification of cloth deformation for further robotic manipulation.

Institute of Photonic Sciences (ICFO)

Barcelona, Spain

Research Intern

June 2017 – August 2017

- Collaboration in the Theoretical Quantum-Nano Photonics group, supervised by Prof. Darrick Chang.
- Project focused on the development of a Fourier-transformation-based algorithm for image compression.

Projects

GPS Telegram Bot

Barcelona, Spain

April 2020 - June 2020

- Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)
- Developed a Telegram bot (coded in Python) providing live-location guidance.
- The bot provides detailed instructions on the fastest route from the current location to a demanded destination.
- Technical Skills: Python, Algorithmics.

OCTOBER 1, 2022

Skills

Programming Python, R, C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Matlab, Hadoop, Spark, Dart.

Miscellaneous Linux, LTFX, Microsoft Office, Firebase, Git.

Machine Learning Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Image Processing, NLP, Time Series.

Achievements _____

2022	Poster presentation at the 2022 INCF Assembly	Stockholm, Sweden
2021	First place in The Barcelona Challenge - FME datathon	Barcelona, Spain
2018	Academic scholarship for full tuition at CFIS-UPC (University)	Barcelona, Spain
2017	Finalist in the National Olympiad in Informatics	Barcelona, Spain
2017	Finalist in the National Olympiad in Physics	Barcelona, Spain
2016	Academic scholarship for full tuition at Aula Escola Europea (HS)	Barcelona, Spain

Interests _____

Teaching Private individual teacher and University academy teacher.

Programming Multiple participations in Datathons and Codeforces

Sports Federated Basketball player; U-14, U-16 & U-18 Basketball Coach

Volunteering Assistance on a local food bank

Languages _____

Spanish Native

English Professional proficiency

Catalan Native